

Abbass Monzer

Date of birth: 15/10/1997 | **Phone number:** (+961) 76947200 (Mobile) | **Email address:**

abbassmonzer1997@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am a dedicated software developer committed to ongoing self-improvement where I actively pursue courses in cutting-edge technologies, particularly in development and artificial intelligence. My expertise extends to project management and design. I have also successfully undertaken freelance projects with international companies, broadening my global perspective and contributing to my commitment to technological innovation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2023 - CURRENT Beirut, Lebanon

FULL STACK DEVELOPER KLEVR

- Developing client-side software for a range of industries, including banking and insurance using React and Next.js.
- Collaborating with a cross-functional team of 10+ members to successfully deliver web applications and projects.
- Designing and implementing responsive user interfaces with Tailwind CSS to ensure a user-friendly appearance.
- Implementing API middleware and developed server-side applications using Nest.js.
- Utilizing Strapi as the headless CMS to manage and structure content, making it easily accessible and customizable.
- Working on the server-side development using Node.js and Strapi and handling API integrations.

05/2022 - 08/2023 Beirut, Lebanon

FRONTEND DEVELOPER ECOMZ

- Developing client-side software for an E-commerce solution using Angular 13 and React.
- Collaborated with a team of 20-25 members to deliver required tasks
- Delivered required tasks using Typescript, HTML5, SCSS, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Ensured high performance and responsiveness to requests from the front end.
- Assisting with workflow coordination between the front-end team and UI/UX product team.
- · Collaborated with the back-end development team to implement RESTful API endpoints

04/2021 - 04/2022 Remote - London, United Kingdom

FULL STACK DEVELOPER ASTRATERRA

- Developing an Intelligent Transport Systems solutions using Angular 11 framework.
- Collaborated with a team of 15-20 members to deliver required tasks.
- Delivered required design tasks using JavaScript, HTML5, SCSS, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Responsible for developing and maintaining Web Application projects using. Netcore.
- Worked on the server-side logic using . Netcore and SQL database.

11/2019 - 03/2021 Beirut, Lebanon

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER BLUERING

- Developing client side for a retail credit management solution using the Angular 9 framework.
- Collaborated with a team of 20-25 members to deliver required tasks.
- Delivered required design tasks using JavaScript, HTML5, SCSS, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Ensuring high performance and responsiveness to requests from the front end.
- Worked on the server-side logic using Java and OracleDB.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

10/2019 - 07/2021 Beirut, Lebanon

MASTER'S DEGREE IN MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEM Lebanese University

BACHELOR DEGREE IN MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEM Lebanese University

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **ARABIC**Other language(s): **ENGLISH**

DIGITAL SKILLS

Frontend

Angular | SCSS | CSS | React | HTML | Bootstrap | Javascript | Next.js | Tailwind | Typescript

Backend

.Netcore | Nodejs | JSON | StrapiCMS | NestJS Framework

Database & DevOps

MongoDB | SQL | PostageSQL | Docker

Version Control & Collaboration

Github | Git | Gitlab | Jira